<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<add xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
   <doc>
      <field name="id">wfc.css00015</field>
      <field name="itemCategory">texts</field>
      <field name="titleMain">Letter from William F. Cody to Charles G. Penney, January 5, 1894</field>
      <field name="category">Texts</field>
      <field name="subCategory">Correspondence</field>
      <field name="date">January 5, 1894</field>
      <field name="dateSearch">1894-01-05</field>
      <field name="year">1894</field>
      <field name="author">Cody, William Frederick, 1846-1917</field>
      <field name="topic">Show Indians</field>
      <field name="keywords">Frontier and pioneer life -- West (U.S.)</field>
      <field name="people">Penney, Charles G</field>
      <field name="people">Salsbury, Nathan</field>
      <field name="places">Pine Ridge Indian Reservation (S.D.)</field>
      <field name="imageID">wfc.css00015_img_0</field>
      <field name="text"> 
        



            

  
  
  North Platte Neb
  Jan. 5th 94
  



  Capt. Chas. G. Penney
  Agt. Pine Ridge
  S. Dak

  

  Dear Capt.
  

  Mr. Salsbury has just sent me the Form of Agreement for the Indians drawn by yourself.1  we both approve of it.  And Just what we have wanted the Indians to for years.  But as their contract was up or made out this way before  they wished their money as soon as the show closed.  but this will be much better for them each and all will have a little money when they arrive at the Agency. 2 this way

  Accept our sincere thanks for your kindly interest

  Wishing you a happily New Year.


  
  Very truly yours
  W. F. Cody








Note 1: The Wild West's employment contracts with Indian performers had to be approved by the agent in charge of the reservation where the Indians resided.  In this case, it appears that Agent Penney took an active role in drafting the contracts himself.

Note 2: Cody refers to the practice of withholding a portion of an Indian performer's salary until the individual returned to the reservation at the end of the show season.  This was a common element in Wild West Indian contracts for the remainder of Cody's show career.

</field>
   </doc>
</add>