<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<add xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
   <doc>
      <field name="id">wfc.his.00001</field>
      <field name="itemCategory">texts</field>
      <field name="titleMain">Historiography</field>
      <field name="category">Scholarship</field>
      <field name="subCategory">Historiography</field>
      <field name="date"/>
      <field name="dateSearch"/>
      <field name="year"/>
      <field name="author">Christianson, Frank</field>
      <field name="topic"/>
      <field name="keywords"/>
      <field name="people"/>
      <field name="places"/>
      <field name="imageID">icon-historiography</field>
      <field name="text"> 





Historiography

Blackstone, Sarah. Buckskin, Bullets and Business: A History of  Buffalo Bill’s Wild West. Westport: Greenwood Press, 1986. 

Black Elk, Nicholas and John G. Neihardt, Black Elk Speaks: 	Being the Life Story of a Holy Man of the Oglala Sioux. Lincoln: University of Nebraska Press, 2004

Buffalo Bill. Story of the Wild West and Camp-Fire Chats by Buffalo Bill. Philadelphia: Historical Publishing Company, 1888. 

Buntline, Ned. Buffalo Bill: The King of the Border Men. Davenport, IA: Service Press, 1869; 1987. 

Burke, John M. “Buffalo Bill” from Prairie to Palace: An Authentic History of the Wild West, with Sketches, Stories 	of Adventure and Anecdotes of “Buffalo Bill,” the Hero of the Plains, Lincoln: University of Nebraska Press, 2012. 

Carter, Robert A. Buffalo Bill Cody: The Man Behind the Legend. New York: Wiley, 2002. 

Davies, Henry Eugene. Ten Days on the Plains. New York: Crocker &amp; Co., 1871. 

Foote, Stella A. Letters from "Buffalo Bill". El Segundo: Upton, 1978. 

Gray, John S. "Fact Versus Fiction in the Kansas Boyhood of Buffalo Bill." Kansas History. 8 (Spring 1985): 2-20. 

Greene, Jerome A. Battles and Skirmishes of the Great Sioux War, 1876-1877: The Military View. Norman: University of Oklahoma Press, 1993. 

Hall, Roger. Performing the American Frontier, 1870-1906. New York: Cambridge University Press, 2001. 

Hedren, Paul L., and Don Russell. First Scalp for Custer: The Skirmish at Warbonnet Creek, Nebraska, July 17, 1876, with a Short History of the Warbonnet Battlefield. Glendale: Arthur H. Clark, 1980. 

Kasson, Joy S. Buffalo Bill's Wild West: Celebrity, Memory, and Popular History. New York: Hill and Wang, 2000. 

Leonard, Elizabeth Jane, and Julia Cody Goodman. Buffalo Bill, King of the Old West: Biography of William F. Cody, Pony Express Rider, Buffalo Hunter, Plains Scout &amp; Guide, Master Showman. Ed. James Williams Hoffman. New York: Library Publishers, 1955. 

Russell, Don. The Lives and Legends of Buffalo Bill. Norman: University of Oklahoma Press, 1979. 

Rydell, Robert W., “London’s American Exhibition of 1887: How a Cultural Farce became a Political Force.” Over (T)here: Transatlantic Essays in Honor of Rob Kroes. Ed. Kate Delaney and Ruud Janssens. Amsterdam: VU University Press, 	2005. 

Rydell, Robert W., and Rob Kroes. Buffalo Bill in Bologna: the Americanization of the world, 1869-1922. Chicago: 	University of Chicago Press, 2005. 
 
Sagala, Sandra K. Buffalo Bill on Stage. 2008: University of New Mexico Press, 2008. 

Slotkin, Richard. Gunfighter Nation: The Myth of the Frontier in Twentieth-Century America. Norman: University of Oklahoma 	Press, 1998.

Standing Bear, Luther. My People the Sioux. Lincoln: Bison Books, 2006. 

Warren, Louis S. Buffalo Bill's America: William Cody and the Wild West Show. First Edition ed. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 2005.

Wetmore, Helen Cody. Last of the Great Scouts: The Life Story of Colonel William F. Cody. The Duluth Press Printing Company: Chicago, 1899. 

White, Richard, and Patricia Nelson Limerick. The Frontier in American Culture: An Exhibition at the Newberry Library, August 26, 1994-January 7, 1995. Ed. James Grossman. Berkeley: University of California Press, 1994. 










</field>
   </doc>
</add>