<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://jetson.unl.edu/cdrh/schemas/tei_all.rng"  type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="wfc.000.scholarship">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title type="main">Scholarship</title>
<author/>
<principal>Johnston, Jeremy</principal>
<principal>Christianson, Frank</principal>
<principal>Seefeldt, Douglas, 1964-</principal>
</titleStmt>
<editionStmt>
<edition>
    <date>2011</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
<publicationStmt>
<authority>William F. Cody Archive</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
    <address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska&#8211;Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unlnotes.unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<pubPlace>Lincoln, Nebraska</pubPlace>
<address>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
</address>

<availability>
    <p/>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>

<notesStmt>
<note><!-- notes that pertain to the entire file can be placed here; the note tag can be repeated as often as necessary within the notesStmt --></note>
</notesStmt>

<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
    <author/>
    <title level="m" type="main">Scholarship</title>

    <extent>1 page</extent>
</bibl>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

<encodingDesc>
<editorialDecl>
<correction>
    <p/>
</correction>
<normalization>
    <p/>
</normalization>
</editorialDecl>
</encodingDesc>

<profileDesc> </profileDesc>

</teiHeader>

<text>
<body>

<div1 type="html">

  <h2>Roosevelt's Rough Riders</h2>

    <a class="btn" href="../../category/result.html?q=topic:%22Roosevelt%27s%20Rough%20Riders%22">Go to Results</a>
<figure class="topic_image">
      <img src="http://codyarchive.org/figures/250/wfc.img.pho.710235.jpg" alt="Congress of Rough Riders"/>
      <figcaption>US Cavalry of Buffalo Bill&#39;s Wild West and Congress of Rough Riders (n.d.)</figcaption>
  </figure>
  <p>
  
  When the United States declared war on Spain in 1898, Theodore Roosevelt resigned as Assistant
  Secretary of the Navy to organize the 1st Volunteer Cavalry with Colonel Leonard Wood. Roosevelt
  reached out to a mix of volunteers, mostly westerners, including many cowboys, from New Mexico,
  Arizona, and the Indian Territory (now Oklahoma), which provided many American Indian recruits. The
  regiment also recruited well-to-do Easterners who graduated from Ivy League universities such as
  Harvard and Yale. Members of the press and others recommended various nicknames, including
  “Teddy’s Terrors” and “Cowboy Cavalry,” yet everyone eventually settled on the name “Rough Riders.”
  Buffalo Bill Cody used the term “The Congress of Rough Riders of the World” beginning in 1893, and
  Roosevelt initially disliked the application of the name Rough Riders to his regiment due to his concerns
  many may view the group as “a hippodrome affair.” The popularity of the moniker won over Roosevelt
  and he eventually embraced the name “Roosevelt’s Rough Riders.”</p>
  <p>Despite training in Texas as a cavalry unit, the Rough Riders arrived in Cuba to fight the Spanish without
  their horses. Lieutenant Colonel Roosevelt and Colonel Wood led the group through the Battle of Las
  Guasimas after landing in Cuba. Roosevelt, now promoted to colonel, led the unit at the Battle of San
  Juan Heights were he and his men secured Kettle Hill and then joined the 10th US Cavalry composed of
  Buffalo Soldiers. The popularity of the Rough Rider regiment propelled Roosevelt through his political
  career leading him to the presidency, yet he never did offer credit to Buffalo Bill for originating the
  name. Despite the perceived slight, in March 1899 Buffalo Bill’s Wild West first staged a reenactment of
  the Battle of San Juan Hill at Madison Square Garden, featuring soldiers who served under Roosevelt
  and members of the 10th Cavalry. This reenactment and others, including the Boxer Rebellion, not only
  reflected Buffalo Bill’s method of using authentic participants to recreate past events, but also signified
  how the Wild West program’s focus on westward expansion continued to accommodate American
  imperialism overseas.</p>
  <p>Funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities and private donors.</p>

  <a class="btn" href="../../category/result.html?q=topic:%22Roosevelt%27s%20Rough%20Riders%22">Go to Results</a>

  </div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>

